<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Cybarspace | A home for my thoughts</title><link>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Cybarspace | A home for my thoughts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Sheikh Saad © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 22:36:56 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Java Lists</title><link>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/java-lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 22:36:56 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/java-lists/</guid><description>PS: This post is structured similarly to my post about arrays . I will also refer to array concepts, so you may want to read that first if you&amp;rsquo;re new to Java collections.
What are lists? Think of lists like a row of cardboard boxes. These boxes can be used to store different types of data - ints, Strings, even custom data types like Person. You can add more boxes to the row, remove boxes from the row, or even have no boxes at all!</description></item><item><title>My Experience with Online Learning</title><link>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/online-learning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 13:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/online-learning/</guid><description>My Story I&amp;rsquo;m currently an undergraduate student studying at Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s University, Nova Scotia, Canada. As my major, I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen Computer Science (they call it computing science, but it&amp;rsquo;s practically the same thing), as I had a keen interest in computers, science and technology from a very young age. Because of the ongoing pandemic, our school has decided to provide online classes with some optional in-person experiences. To save money on residence, food and other costs, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to do online classes from Bangladesh until in-person classes fully begin.</description></item><item><title>Java Arrays</title><link>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/java-arrays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 16:03:05 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/java-arrays/</guid><description>What are arrays? Think of arrays like a row of cardboard boxes. These boxes can be used to store different types of data - ints, Strings, even custom data types like Person.
One important thing to note is that you can only have a constant number of these boxes for each array you make. While making the array, if you tell Java that this array will have 10 items, then that array will always be able to contain up to 10 items - no more, no less, no changes to this size.</description></item><item><title>Prefix (++i) vs Postfix (i++) Operators in Code</title><link>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/prefix-vs-postfix/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 21:40:48 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://www.cybarspace.dev/blog/prefix-vs-postfix/</guid><description>The dilemma: ++i vs i++ In C-style languages (C, C++, Java, etc.), the operators ++ and -- are used to add or subtract 1 from a variable. ++ is called the “increment” operator, and -- is called the “decrement” operator. If the operator is put before the variable, as in ++i, it’s called a “prefix” operator. If the operator is put after the variable, as in i--, it’s called a “postfix operator” or “suffix operator”.</description></item></channel></rss>